Summa

Summary

Data Science & Artificial Intelligence: 10+ years applying econometrics and machine learning, and other advanced methods to quantify what is often thought of as unquantifiable. Guest lecturer in statistics course at UCLA.

Business Acumen: 8+ years using business consulting skills to improve business outcomes (+\$500 million) in the entertainment, retail, and economic consulting industries. Mentor to UCLA MBA students focusing on technology.

Strategic Leadership: 5+ years attracting and developing (hard/soft skills) high-performing data science teams. Responsible for self-directed learning of 400+ employees through NBCU Professional Development Committee.

Experience

Director | Algorithm Innovation

20th Century Fox [Oct. 2017 - Present]

- · Defining and managing key individual milestones; coordinating with key stakeholders; producing insights into decision making tools
- Hands-on artificial intelligence / deep learning model development of natural language using Spark, Python, TensorFlow
- Manage co-development projects with R&D partners to continuously challenge/improve interpretation of social media
- Data preparation of streaming data; applying ML models, and implementing end-to-end, production ready machine learning models

Director | Analytics

NBCUniversal [Jan. 2016 – Oct. 2017]

- Championing algorithm-driven decision making in the organization from executive buy-in to the management of complex projects
- Expanded digital revenues (100%+) in particular territories by optimizing release strategies through hands-on statistical modeling
- Reduced sales forecast errors (risk) by 50% through hands-on machine learning in R, data integration (MySQL), Tableau visualization
- Attracted and hired top-tier analytics talent (PhD, Ivy League MBAs) through personal connections (Linkedin 7000+ connections)

Manager | Management Science & Integration

The Walt Disney Company [2012 - 2015]

- Delivered \$20-\$40M in incremental ad sales revenue for ABC Television through hands on machine learning and econometrics
- Promoted in less than a year in Disney's Central Internal Advanced Analytics team (30+ PhDs) based on leadership and technical skills
- Hired 3 top-tier analytics resources in 3 months after developing case studies (McKinsey style) and rigorous statistical screeners

Senior Analyst | Corporate Brand Management

- Subject matter expert on advanced analytics for highly-influential (ex CIA, ex McKinsey, ex Bain) group in Corporate Strategy
- Informed senior executives on TVs contribution to revenues through the use of Nobel Prize winning economic modeling

Analyst | Economics & Statistics

Econ One Research [2011 - 2012]

- Lead programmer/analyst on project resulting in \$400M settlement in litigation case involving Google, Apple, and Disney
- Estimated \$65M dollar Korean Air using advanced econometric models to quantify impact of price-fixing scheme
- Programmatically integrated data (SQL) from multiple sources for PhD economists resulting in a \$125M settlement in TV price fixing

Analyst | Planning & Forecasting

Pacific Sunwear [2010 - 2011]

- Hired as quantitative expert in centralized planning department to tackle illusive and high-profile advanced analytics projects
- Reduced forecast error by 23% after scraping arithmetic based Excel method and replacing with machine learning process
- Increased store revenues by 8% by replacing rudimentary pricing strategy with 1000+ regression based pricing models

Research Assistant | Finance

UCLA Anderson School of Management [2007 - 2009]

• Work-study under Professor Emeritus of Finance, Fred Weston (mentor of Nobel Prize winning economists), on stock analysis

Education

M.A. Economics, Econometrics, Time Series Analysis

California State University, Fullerton – Mihaylo College of Business and Economics

- Financial accounting (MBA course)
- Production optimization (calculus based)
- Advanced statistical forecasting

- Consumer Choice Modeling (calculus based)
- Quantitative Macroeconomics
- Advanced econometric modeling

B.S. Mathematics/Applied Science

UCLA

- Mathematical statistics/probability
- Quantitative chemistry and biology
- Advanced multivariable calculus

- Engineering and planetary physics (astrophysics)
- Game Theory (strategic decision making)
- Computer programming (C++, STATA)

B.A. Economics

UCLA

- International finance (calculus based)
- Financial markets/investments
- International trade (calculus based)

• Probabilistic microeconomics (behavioral economics)

Building cognitive models on data (deep learning)

Perception models based on brain function (neurons)

- Financial accounting
- Real Estate Investing and Business Law

Certifications & Trainings

(full list of 20+ certifications available here)

Executive Data Science Specialization

Johns Hopkins University – MOOC

- Building data science teams
- Managing data science projects

Competing on Analytics

Harvard University (Executive Education) (2018)

- Enterprise leadership for advanced analytics
- Executive training on data driven initiatives

Digital Marketing

Coursera - MOOC

University of Pennsylvania (Wharton) – MOOC

- The consumer journey
- Brand management

High-Potentials Leadership Program

Disney University & Harvard Mentor

- Project management
- Executive communication

Big Data Technology Fundamentals

Artificial Intelligence Specialization

Amazon Web Service (AWS)

- Overview of Big Data technology (AWS)
- Business use cases of Big Data

Volunteer Experiences

Technology Focused MBA Mentor

UCLA Anderson School of Management [2017]

- Easton Technology Center Industry Mentor
- Mentoring students on machine learning/technology

Director of Education

National Association of Business Economists

- Provided 50+ scholarships to economics students
- Partnered with US Federal Reserve Bank for events

Guest Lecturer | Econometrics

UCLA Economics Department [2011 - 2016]

- Public speaking to 300+ students per year
- One-on-one mentoring with Sharpe Fellows

Director of Finance

Global Business Brigades

- ROI modeling of agricultural production in Honduras
- Accounting during non-profit certification